Reddit User Agreement
Effective October 15, 2020. Last Revised September 15, 2020
Reddit powers hundreds of thousands of distinct online communities.
This User Agreement and your conduct make that possible.

Hello, redditors and people of the Internet! This Reddit User Agreement ("Terms") applies to your access to and use of the websites, mobile apps, widgets, APIs, emails, and other online products and services (collectively, the "Services") provided by Reddit, Inc. ("Reddit," "we," "us," or "our").

Remember Reddit is for fun and is intended to be a place for your entertainment, but we still need some basic rules. By accessing or using our Services, you agree to be bound by these Terms. If you do not agree to these Terms, you may not access or use our Services.

Please take a look at Reddit's Privacy Policy too-it explains how and why we collect, use, and share information about you when you access or use our Services.

1. Your Access to the Services
Children under the age of 13 are not allowed to create an Account or otherwise use the Services. Additionally, you must be over the age required by the laws of your country to create an account or otherwise use the Services, or we need to have received verifiable consent from your parent or legal guardian.

In addition, certain of our Services or portions of our Services require you to be 18 years of age or older, so please read all notices and any Additional Terms carefully when you access the Services.

If you are accepting these Terms on behalf of another legal entity, including a business or government entity, you represent that you have full legal authority to bind such entity to these Terms.

2. Your Use of the Services
Reddit grants you a personal, non-transferable, non-exclusive, revocable, limited license to use and access the Services solely as permitted by these Terms. We reserve all rights not expressly granted to you by these Terms.

Except as permitted through the Services or as otherwise permitted by us in writing, your license does not include the right to:

license, sell, transfer, assign, distribute, host, or otherwise commercially exploit the Services or Content;
modify, prepare derivative works of, disassemble, decompile, or reverse engineer any part of the Services or Content; or
access the Services or Content in order to build a similar or competitive website, product, or service, except as permitted under the Reddit API Terms of Use.
We reserve the right to modify, suspend, or discontinue the Services (in whole or in part) at any time, with or without notice to you. Any future release, update, or other addition to functionality of the Services will be subject to these Terms, which may be updated from time to time. You agree that we will not be liable to you or to any third party for any modification, suspension, or discontinuation of the Services or any part thereof.

3. Your Reddit Account and Account Security
To use certain features of our Services, you may be required to create a Reddit account (an "Account") and provide us with a username, password, and certain other information about yourself as set forth in the Privacy Policy.

You are solely responsible for the information associated with your Account and anything that happens related to your Account. You must maintain the security of your Account and immediately notify Reddit if you discover or suspect that someone has accessed your Account without your permission. We recommend that you use a strong password that is used only with your Account and enable two-factor authentication.

You will not license, sell, or transfer your Account without our prior written approval.

4. Your Content
The Services may contain information, text, links, graphics, photos, videos, or other materials ("Content"), including Content created or submitted to the Services by you or through your Account ("Your Content"). We take no responsibility for and we do not expressly or implicitly endorse, support, or guarantee the completeness, truthfulness, accuracy, or reliability of any of Your Content.

By submitting Your Content to the Services, you represent and warrant that you have all rights, power, and authority necessary to grant the rights to Your Content contained within these Terms. Because you alone are responsible for Your Content, you may expose yourself to liability if you post or share Content without all necessary rights.

You retain any ownership rights you have in Your Content, but you grant Reddit the following license to use that Content:

When Your Content is created with or submitted to the Services, you grant us a worldwide, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, non-exclusive, transferable, and sublicensable license to use, copy, modify, adapt, prepare derivative works of, distribute, store, perform, and display Your Content and any name, username, voice, or likeness provided in connection with Your Content in all media formats and channels now known or later developed anywhere in the world. This license includes the right for us to make Your Content available for syndication, broadcast, distribution, or publication by other companies, organizations, or individuals who partner with Reddit. You also agree that we may remove metadata associated with Your Content, and you irrevocably waive any claims and assertions of moral rights or attribution with respect to Your Content.

Any ideas, suggestions, and feedback about Reddit or our Services that you provide to us are entirely voluntary, and you agree that Reddit may use such ideas, suggestions, and feedback without compensation or obligation to you.

Although we have no obligation to screen, edit, or monitor Your Content, we may, in our sole discretion, delete or remove Your Content at any time and for any reason, including for violating these Terms, violating our Content Policy, or if you otherwise create or are likely to create liability for us.

5. Third-Party Content, Advertisements, and Promotions
The Services may contain links to third-party websites, products, or services, which may be posted by advertisers, our affiliates, our partners, or other users ("Third-Party Content"). Third-Party Content is not under our control, and we are not responsible for any third party's websites, products, or services. Your use of Third-Party Content is at your own risk and you should make any investigation you feel necessary before proceeding with any transaction in connection with such Third-Party Content.

The Services may also contain sponsored Third-Party Content or advertisements. The type, degree, and targeting of advertisements are subject to change, and you acknowledge and agree that we may place advertisements in connection with the display of any Content or information on the Services, including Your Content.

If you choose to use the Services to conduct a promotion, including a contest or sweepstakes ("Promotion"), you alone are responsible for conducting the Promotion in compliance with all applicable laws and regulations at your own risk. Your Promotion must state that the Promotion is not sponsored by, endorsed by, or associated with Reddit, and the rules for your Promotion must require each entrant or participant to release Reddit from any liability related to the Promotion.

6. Things You Cannot Do
When using or accessing Reddit, you must comply with these Terms and all applicable laws, rules, and regulations. Please review the Content Policy (and for RPAN, the Broadcasting Content Policy), which are part of these Terms and contain Reddit's rules about prohibited content and conduct. In addition to what is prohibited in the Content Policy, you may not do any of the following:

Use the Services in any manner that could interfere with, disable, disrupt, overburden, or otherwise impair the Services.
Gain access to (or attempt to gain access to) another user's Account or any non-public portions of the Services, including the computer systems or networks connected to or used together with the Services.
Upload, transmit, or distribute to or through the Services any viruses, worms, malicious code, or other software intended to interfere with the Services, including its security-related features.
Use the Services to violate applicable law or infringe any person's or entity's intellectual property rights or any other proprietary rights.
Access, search, or collect data from the Services by any means (automated or otherwise) except as permitted in these Terms or in a separate agreement with Reddit. We conditionally grant permission to crawl the Services in accordance with the parameters set forth in our robots.txt file, but scraping the Services without Reddit's prior consent is prohibited.
Use the Services in any manner that we reasonably believe to be an abuse of or fraud on Reddit or any payment system.
We encourage you to report content or conduct that you believe violates these Terms or our Content Policy. We also support the responsible reporting of security vulnerabilities. To report a security issue, please email security@reddit.com.

7. Moderators
Moderating a subreddit is an unofficial, voluntary position that may be available to users of the Services. We are not responsible for actions taken by the moderators. We reserve the right to revoke or limit a user's ability to moderate at any time and for any reason or no reason, including for a breach of these Terms.

If you choose to moderate a subreddit:

You agree to follow the Moderator Guidelines for Healthy Communities;
You agree that when you receive reports related to a subreddit you moderate, you will take appropriate action, which may include removing content that violates policy and/or promptly escalating to Reddit for review;
You are not, and may not represent that you are, authorized to act on behalf of Reddit;
You may not enter into any agreement with a third party on behalf of Reddit, or any subreddits that you moderate, without our written approval;
You may not perform moderation actions in return for any form of compensation, consideration, gift, or favor from third parties;
If you have access to non-public information as a result of moderating a subreddit, you will use such information only in connection with your performance as a moderator; and
You may create and enforce rules for the subreddits you moderate, provided that such rules do not conflict with these Terms, the Content Policy, or the Moderator Guidelines for Healthy Communities.
Reddit reserves the right, but has no obligation, to overturn any action or decision of a moderator if Reddit, in its sole discretion, believes that such action or decision is not in the interest of Reddit or the Reddit community.

8. Copyright, Trademark, the DMCA, and Takedowns
Reddit respects the intellectual property of others and requires that users of our Services do the same. We have a policy that includes the removal of any infringing material from the Services and for the termination, in appropriate circumstances, of users of our Services who are repeat infringers. If you believe that anything on our Services infringes a copyright or a trademark that you own or control, you may notify Reddit's Designated Agent by filling out our Copyright Report Form or Trademark Report Form, or by contacting:

Copyright Agent
Reddit, Inc.
1455 Market Street, Suite 1600
San Francisco, CA 94103
copyright@reddit.com

Also, please note that if you knowingly misrepresent that any activity or material on our Service is infringing, you may be liable to Reddit for certain costs and damages.

If we remove Your Content in response to a copyright or trademark notice, we will notify you via Reddit's private messaging system. If you believe Your Content was wrongly removed due to a mistake or misidentification in a copyright notice, you can send a counter notification via our Copyright Counter Notice Form or to our Copyright Agent (contact information provided above). Please see 17 U.S.C. § 512(g)(3) for the requirements of a proper counter notification.

9. Paid Services and Payment Information
There are no fees for the use of many aspects of the Services. However, some services, including Reddit Premium and Virtual Goods, may be available for purchase ("Paid Services"). In addition to these Terms, by purchasing or using Reddit Premium or our Virtual Goods, you further agree to the Reddit Premium and Virtual Goods Agreement.

Reddit may change the fees or benefits associated with the Paid Services from time to time with reasonable advance notice of material changes; provided, however, that no advance notice will be required for temporary promotions, including temporary reductions in the fees associated with the Paid Services.

You may submit your debit card, credit card, or other payment information ("Payment Information") via our Services to purchase the Paid Services. We use third-party service providers to process your Payment Information. If you submit your Payment Information, you agree to pay all costs that you incur, and you give us permission to charge you when payment is due for an amount that includes these costs and any applicable taxes and fees.

10. Indemnity
Except to the extent prohibited by law, you agree to defend, indemnify, and hold us, our directors, officers, employees, affiliates, agents, contractors, third-party service providers, and licensors (the "Reddit Entities") harmless from any claim or demand, including costs and attorneys' fees, made by any third party due to or arising out of (a) your use of the Services, (b) your violation of these Terms, (c) your violation of applicable laws or regulations, or (d) Your Content. We reserve the right to control the defense of any matter for which you are required to indemnify us, and you agree to cooperate with our defense of these claims.

11. Disclaimers
THE SERVICES ARE PROVIDED "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" WITHOUT WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, TITLE, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. REDDIT ENTITIES DO NOT WARRANT THAT THE SERVICES ARE ACCURATE, COMPLETE, RELIABLE, CURRENT, OR ERROR FREE. REDDIT DOES NOT CONTROL, ENDORSE, OR TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY CONTENT AVAILABLE ON OR LINKED TO THE SERVICES OR THE ACTIONS OF ANY THIRD PARTY OR USER, INCLUDING MODERATORS. WHILE REDDIT ATTEMPTS TO MAKE YOUR ACCESS TO AND USE OF OUR SERVICES SAFE, WE DO NOT REPRESENT OR WARRANT THAT OUR SERVICES OR SERVERS ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS.

12. Limitation of Liability
IN NO EVENT AND UNDER NO THEORY OF LIABILITY, INCLUDING CONTRACT, TORT, NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY, WARRANTY, OR OTHERWISE, WILL THE REDDIT ENTITIES BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ANY INDIRECT, CONSEQUENTIAL, EXEMPLARY, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES, OR LOST PROFITS ARISING FROM OR RELATING TO THESE TERMS OR THE SERVICES, INCLUDING THOSE ARISING FROM OR RELATING TO CONTENT MADE AVAILABLE ON THE SERVICES THAT IS ALLEGED TO BE DEFAMATORY, OFFENSIVE, OR ILLEGAL. ACCESS TO, AND USE OF, THE SERVICES IS AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK, AND YOU WILL BE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR DEVICE OR COMPUTER SYSTEM, OR LOSS OF DATA RESULTING THEREFROM. IN NO EVENT WILL THE AGGREGATE LIABILITY OF THE REDDIT ENTITIES EXCEED THE GREATER OF ONE HUNDRED U.S. DOLLARS ($100) OR ANY AMOUNT YOU PAID REDDIT IN THE PREVIOUS SIX MONTHS FOR THE SERVICES GIVING RISE TO THE CLAIM. THE LIMITATIONS OF THIS SECTION WILL APPLY TO ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, INCLUDING THOSE BASED ON WARRANTY, CONTRACT, STATUTE, TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE) OR OTHERWISE, AND EVEN IF THE REDDIT ENTITIES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH DAMAGE, AND EVEN IF ANY REMEDY SET FORTH HEREIN IS FOUND TO HAVE FAILED ITS ESSENTIAL PURPOSE. THE FOREGOING LIMITATION OF LIABILITY WILL APPLY TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW IN THE APPLICABLE JURISDICTION.

13. Governing Law and Venue
We want you to enjoy Reddit, so if you have an issue or dispute, you agree to raise it and try to resolve it with us informally. You can contact us with feedback and concerns here.

Except for the government entities listed below, any claims arising out of or relating to these Terms or the Services will be governed by the laws of California, without regard to its conflict of laws rules. All disputes related to these Terms or the Services will be brought solely in the federal or state courts located in San Francisco, California, and you consent to personal jurisdiction in these courts.

Government Entities
If you are a U.S. city, county, or state government entity, then this Section 13 does not apply to you.

If you are a U.S. federal government entity, any claims arising out of or relating to these Terms or the Services will be governed by the laws of the United States of America without regard to its conflict of laws rules. To the extent permitted by federal law, the laws of California (other than its conflict of law rules) will apply in the absence of applicable federal law. All disputes related to these Terms or the Services will be brought solely in the federal or state courts located in San Francisco, California.

14. Changes to these Terms
We may make changes to these Terms from time to time. If we make changes, we will post the revised Terms and update the Effective Date above. If the changes, in our sole discretion, are material, we may also notify you by sending an email to the address associated with your Account (if you have chosen to provide an email address) or by otherwise providing notice through our Services. By continuing to access or use the Services on or after the Effective Date of the revised Terms, you agree to be bound by the revised Terms. If you do not agree to the revised Terms, you must stop accessing and using our Services before the changes become effective.

15. Additional Terms
Because we offer a variety of Services, you may be asked to agree to additional terms before using a specific product or service offered by Reddit ("Additional Terms"). To the extent any Additional Terms conflict with these Terms, the Additional Terms govern with respect to your use of the corresponding Service.

If you use Reddit Premium or Virtual Goods, you must also agree to the Reddit Premium and Virtual Goods Agreement.

If you use the self-service platform for advertising, you must also agree to our Reddit Advertising Platform Terms.

If you use our public API, you must also agree to our Reddit API Terms of Use.

If you use Reddit Gifts, you must agree to the Reddit Gifts User Agreement.

16. Termination
You may terminate these Terms at any time and for any reason by deleting your Account and discontinuing use of all Services. If you stop using the Services without deactivating your Account, your Account may be deactivated due to prolonged inactivity.

We may suspend or terminate your Account, moderator status, or ability to access or use the Services at any time for any or no reason, including for violating these Terms or our Content Policy.

The following sections will survive any termination of these Terms or of your Account: 4 (Your Content), 6 (Things You Cannot Do), 10 (Indemnity), 11 (Disclaimers), 12 (Limitation of Liability), 13 (Governing Law and Venue), 16 (Termination), and 17 (Miscellaneous).

17. Miscellaneous
These Terms constitute the entire agreement between you and us regarding your access to and use of the Services. Our failure to exercise or enforce any right or provision of these Terms will not operate as a waiver of such right or provision. If any provision of these Terms is, for any reason, held to be illegal, invalid, or unenforceable, the rest of the Terms will remain in effect. You may not assign or transfer any of your rights or obligations under these Terms without our consent. We may freely assign any of our rights and obligations under these Terms.

Contact Information
Reddit, Inc.
1455 Market Street, Suite 1600
San Francisco, CA 94103
United States

Authorized to receive service in Germany on behalf of Reddit, Inc. for administrative and judicial proceedings within the meaning of Section 5(1) of the Network Enforcement Act:

Taylor Wessing PartG mbB
- NetzDG-Zustellungen -
Am Sandtorkai 41
20457 Hamburg
Germany


Reddit Privacy Policy
Effective October 15, 2020. Last Revised September 15, 2020
We want you to understand how and why Reddit, Inc. ("Reddit," "we" or "us") collects, uses, and shares information about you when you use our sites, mobile apps, widgets, and other online products and services (collectively, the "Services") or when you otherwise interact with us or receive a communication from us. This Privacy Policy applies to all of our Services including Reddit Gifts, which maintains a separate privacy notice that incorporates this Privacy Policy by reference.

What We Collect (and How it is Used and Shared)

Information You Provide to Us
We collect information you provide to us directly when you use the Services. This includes:	

Account information		
If you create a Reddit account, we may require you to provide a username and password. Your username is public, and it doesn't have to be related to your real name. You may also provide other account information, like an email address, bio, or profile picture. We also store your user account preferences and settings.	

Content you submit		
We collect the content you submit to the Services. This includes your posts and comments including saved drafts, videos you broadcast via RPAN, your messages with other users (e.g., private messages, chats, and modmail), and your reports and other communications with moderators and with us. Your content may include text, links, images, gifs, and videos.	

Actions you take		
We collect information about the actions you take when using the Services. This includes your interactions with content, like voting, saving, hiding, and reporting. It also includes your interactions with other users, such as following, friending, and blocking. We collect your interactions with communities, like your subscriptions or moderator status.	

Transactional information		
If you purchase products or services from us (e.g., Reddit Premium or Reddit Coins), we will collect certain information from you, including your name, address, email address, and information about the product or service you are purchasing. Reddit uses industry-standard payment processor services (for example, Stripe) to handle payment information.	

Other information		
You may choose to provide other information directly to us. For example, we may collect information when you fill out a form, participate in Reddit-sponsored activities or promotions, apply for a job, request customer support, or otherwise communicate with us.	


Information We Collect Automatically
When you access or use our Services, we may also automatically collect information about you. This includes:	

Log and usage data		
We may log information when you access and use the Services. This may include your IP address, user-agent string, browser type, operating system, referral URLs, device information (e.g., device IDs), device settings, pages visited, links clicked, the requested URL, and search terms. Except for the IP address used to create your account, Reddit will delete any IP addresses collected after 100 days.	

Information collected from cookies and similar technologies		
We may receive information from cookies, which are pieces of data your browser stores and sends back to us when making requests, and similar technologies. We use this information to improve your experience, understand user activity, personalize content and advertisements, and improve the quality of our Services. For example, we store and retrieve information about your preferred language and other settings. See our Cookie Notice for more information about how Reddit uses cookies. For more information on how you can disable cookies, please see "Your Choices" below.	

Location information


We may receive and process information about your location. For example, with your consent, we may collect information about the specific location of your mobile device (for example, by using GPS or Bluetooth). We may also receive location information from you when you choose to share such information on our Services, including by associating your content with a location, or we may derive your approximate location from other information about you, including your IP address.	


Information Collected from Other Sources
We may receive information about you from other sources, including from other users and third parties, and combine that information with the other information we have about you. For example, we may receive demographic or interest information about you from third parties, including advertisers (such as the fact that an advertiser is interested in showing you an ad), and combine it with our own data using a common account identifier such as a hash of an email address or a mobile-device ID. You can control how we use this information to personalize the Services for you as described in "Your Choices - Controlling Advertising and Analytics" below.	

Linked services		
If you authorize or link a third-party service (e.g., an unofficial mobile app client) to access your Reddit account, Reddit receives information about your use of that service when it uses that authorization. Linking services may also cause the other service to send us information about your account with that service. For example, if you sign in to Reddit with a third-party identity provider, that provider may share an email address with us. To learn how information is shared with linked services, see "How Information About You Is Shared" below.	

Information collected from integrations		
We also may receive information about you, including log and usage data and cookie information, from third-party sites that integrate our Services, including our embeds and advertising technology. For example, when you visit a site that uses Reddit embeds, we may receive information about the web page you visited. Similarly, if an advertiser incorporates Reddit's ad technology, Reddit may receive limited information about your activity on the advertiser's site or app, such as whether you bought something from the advertiser. You can control how we use this information to personalize the Services for you as described in "Your Choices - Controlling Advertising and Analytics" below.	


Information Collected by Third Parties	

Embedded content		
Reddit displays some linked content in-line on the Reddit services via "embeds." For example, Reddit posts that link to YouTube or Twitter may load the linked video or tweet within Reddit directly from those services to your device so you don't have to leave Reddit to see it. In general, Reddit does not control how third-party services collect data when they serve you their content directly via these embeds. As a result, embedded content is not covered by this privacy policy but by the policies of the service from which the content is embedded.	

Programmatic ads		
We partner with third-party programmatic ad exchanges to show advertisements relevant to your interests. In providing those ads, those third parties collect information, including log and usage data and information from cookies as described above. These third parties do not receive any information from your Reddit account.	

Audience measurement		
We partner with audience measurement companies (including Quantcast and Nielsen) to learn demographic information about the population that uses Reddit. To provide this demographic information, these companies collect cookie information to recognize your device.	


Information Collected from Advertisers and Potential Advertisers
If you use Reddit Ads (Reddit's self-serve ads platform at ads.reddit.com) we collect some additional information. To sign up for Reddit Ads, you must provide your name, email address, and information about your company. If you purchase advertising services, you will need to provide transactional information as described above, and we may also require additional documentation to verify your identity. When using Reddit Ads, we may record a session replay of your visit for customer service, troubleshooting, and usability research purposes.	


We use information about you to:

Provide, maintain, and improve the Services;
Research and develop new services;
Help protect the safety of Reddit and our users, which includes blocking suspected spammers, addressing abuse, and enforcing the Reddit User Agreement and our other policies;
Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, invoices, and other support and administrative messages;
Provide customer service;
Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, and events, and provide other news and information we think will be of interest to you (for information about how to opt out of these communications, see "Your Choices" below);
Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Services;
Measure the effectiveness of ads shown on our Services; and
Personalize the Services, and provide and optimize advertisements, content, and features that match user profiles or interests.
Much of the information on the Services is public and accessible to everyone, even without an account. By using the Services, you are directing us to share this information publicly and freely.

When you submit content (including a post, comment, chat message, or RPAN broadcast) to a public part of the Services, any visitors to and users of our Services will be able to see that content, the username associated with the content, and the date and time you originally submitted the content. Reddit allows other sites to embed public Reddit content via our embed tools. Reddit also allows third parties to access public Reddit content via the Reddit API and other similar technologies. Although some parts of the Services may be private or quarantined, they may become public (e.g., at the moderator's option in the case of private communities) and you should take that into consideration before posting to the Services.

Your Reddit account has a profile page that is public. Your profile contains information about your activities on the Services, such as your username, prior posts and comments, karma, awards received, trophies, moderator status, Reddit Premium status, and how long you have been a member of the Services. You can also choose for your profile to include the content you upvote and downvote.

We offer social sharing features that let you share content or actions you take on our Services with other media. Your use of these features enables the sharing of certain information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the third party that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the third parties that provide these social sharing features (e.g., Tumblr, Facebook, and Twitter).

Reddit only shares nonpublic information about you in the following ways. We do not sell this information.

With your consent. We may share information about you with your consent or at your direction.
With linked services. If you link your Reddit account with a third-party service, Reddit will share the information you authorize with that third-party service. You can control this sharing as described in "Your Choices" below.
With our service providers. We may share information with vendors, consultants, and other service providers who need access to such information to carry out work for us. Their use of personal data will be subject to appropriate confidentiality and security measures. A few examples: (i) payment processors who process transactions on our behalf, (ii) cloud providers who host our data and our services, (iii) third-party ads measurement providers who help us and advertisers measure the performance of ads shown on our Services.
To comply with the law. We may share information in response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or governmental request, including, but not limited to, meeting national security or law enforcement requirements. To the extent the law allows it, we will attempt to provide you with prior notice before disclosing your information in response to such a request. Our Transparency Report has additional information about how we respond to government requests.
In an emergency. We may share information if we believe it's necessary to prevent imminent and serious bodily harm to a person.
To enforce our policies and rights. We may share information if we believe your actions are inconsistent with our User Agreement, rules, or other Reddit policies, or to protect the rights, property, and safety of ourselves and others.
With our affiliates. We may share information between and among Reddit, and any of our parents, affiliates, subsidiaries, and other companies under common control and ownership.
Aggregated or de-identified information. We may share information about you that has been aggregated or anonymized such that it cannot reasonably be used to identify you. For example, we may show the total number of times a post has been upvoted without identifying who the visitors were, or we may tell an advertiser how many people saw their ad.
How We Protect Your Information
We take measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. For example, we use HTTPS while information is being transmitted. We also enforce technical and administrative access controls to limit which of our employees have access to nonpublic personal information.

You can help maintain the security of your account by configuring two-factor authentication.

We store the information we collect for as long as it is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. We may retain certain information for legitimate business purposes or as required by law.

Your Choices
You have choices about how to protect and limit the collection, use, and sharing of information about you when you use the Services. Some of these choices are available to everyone who uses Reddit, while others only apply if you have a Reddit account.


Accessing and Changing Your Information		
You can access and change certain information through the Services. See our Help Center page for more information. You can also request a copy of the personal information Reddit maintains about you by following the process described here.	

Deleting Your Account		
You may delete your account information at any time from the user preferences page. You can also submit a request to delete the personal information Reddit maintains about you by following the process described in the "Your Rights - Data Subject and Consumer Information Requests" section below. When you delete your account, your profile is no longer visible to other users and disassociated from content you posted under that account. Please note, however, that the posts, comments, and messages you submitted prior to deleting your account will still be visible to others unless you first delete the specific content. We may also retain certain information about you as required by law or for legitimate business purposes after you delete your account.	

Controlling Linked Services' Access to Your Account		
You can review the services you have permitted to access your account and revoke access to individual services by visiting your account's Apps page (for third-party app authorizations) and the Connected Accounts section of your Account Settings (for Google Sign-In, Sign in with Apple, and connected Twitter accounts).	

Controlling the Use of Cookies		
Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject first- and third-party cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services. For more information on controlling how cookies and similar technologies are used on Reddit, see our Cookie Notice.	

Controlling Advertising and Analytics		
Some analytics providers we partner with may provide specific opt-out mechanisms and we may provide, as needed and as available, additional tools and third-party services that allow you to better understand cookies and how you can opt out. For example, you may manage the use and collection of certain information by Google Analytics via the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. You can opt out of the Audience Measurement services provided by Nielsen and Quantcast.

We also offer you choices about receiving personalized advertisements. You can adjust how we personalize advertisements for you by visiting your ads preferences in your account settings, or here if you use Reddit in a web browser. You can also use device-level settings to control personalized advertisements on Android ("Reset advertising ID" and "Opt out of Ads Personalization") and iOS ("Limit Ad Tracking") devices. You may also generally opt out of receiving personalized advertisements from certain third-party advertisers and ad networks. To learn more about these advertisements or to opt out, please visit the sites of the Digital Advertising Alliance and the Network Advertising Initiative, or if you are a user in the European Economic Area, Your Online Choices.	

Do Not Track		
Most modern web browsers give you the option to send a Do Not Track signal to the sites you visit, indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. However, there is no accepted standard for how a site should respond to this signal, and we do not take any action in response to this signal. Instead, in addition to publicly available third-party tools, we offer you the choices described in this policy to manage the collection and use of information about you.	

Controlling Promotional Communications		
You may opt out of receiving some or all categories of promotional communications from us by following the instructions in those communications or by updating your email options in your account preferences here. If you opt out of promotional communications, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as information about your account or your use of the Services.	

Controlling Mobile Notifications		
With your consent, we may send promotional and non-promotional push notifications or alerts to your mobile device. You can deactivate these messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device.	

Controlling Location Information		
You can control how we use location information inferred from your IP address for content recommendation purposes via the Safety and Privacy settings on your account. If you initially consent to our collection of more precise location information from your device, you can subsequently stop the collection of this information at any time by changing the preferences on your mobile device.	

Your Rights
Data Subject and Consumer Information Requests
Requests for a copy of the information Reddit has about your account-including EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) data subject access requests and California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) consumer information requests-can be submitted following the process described here.

All other data subject and consumer requests under data protection laws should be sent via email to redditdatarequests@reddit.com from the email address that you have verified with your Reddit account.

Before we process a request from you about your personal information, we need to verify the request via your access to your Reddit account or to a verified email address associated with your Reddit account. You may also designate an authorized agent to exercise these rights on your behalf. Reddit does not discriminate against users for exercising their rights under data protection laws to make requests regarding their personal information.

International Data Transfers
We are based in the United States and we process and store information on servers located in the United States. We may store information on servers and equipment in other countries depending on a variety of factors, including the locations of our users and service providers. By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing, transfer, and storage of information in and to the U.S. and other countries, where you may not have the same rights as you do under local law.

In connection with Reddit's processing of personal data received from the European Union, Switzerland, and the United Kingdom, we adhere to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Program ("Privacy Shield") and comply with its framework and principles. Although the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Program may no longer be a valid basis for certain international data transfers, Reddit continues to comply with the Privacy Shield framework and principles with respect to personal data received from the EU in addition to all other applicable laws.

Please direct any inquiries or complaints regarding our compliance with the Privacy Shield principles to the point of contact listed in the "Contact Us" section below. If we do not resolve your complaint, you may submit your complaint free of charge to JAMS. Under certain conditions specified by the Privacy Shield principles, you may also be able to invoke binding arbitration to resolve your complaint. We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. In certain circumstances, we may be liable for the transfer of personal data from the EU, Switzerland, or the UK to a third party outside those countries.

For more information about the Privacy Shield principles and to view our certification, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield site.

Additional Information for EEA Users
Users in the European Economic Area have the right to request access to, rectification of, or erasure of their personal data; to data portability in certain circumstances; to request restriction of processing; to object to processing; and to withdraw consent for processing where they have previously provided consent. These rights can be exercised using the information provided under "Your Choices" above or as described in the "Your Rights - Data Subject and Consumer Information Requests section" above. EEA users also have the right to lodge a complaint with their local supervisory authority.

As required by applicable law, we collect and process information about individuals in the EEA only where we have a legal basis for doing so. Our legal bases depend on the Services you use and how you use them. We process your information on the following legal bases:

You have consented for us to do so for a specific purpose;
We need to process the information to provide you the Services, including to operate the Services, provide customer support and personalized features and to protect the safety and security of the Services;
It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as preventing fraud, ensuring network and information security, enforcing our rules and policies, protecting our legal rights and interests, research and development, personalizing the Services, and marketing and promoting the Services; or
We need to process your information to comply with our legal obligations.
Additional Information for California Users
The California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA") requires us to provide California residents with some additional information about the categories of personal information we collect and share, where we get that personal information, and how and why we use it.

In the last 12 months, we collected the following categories of personal information from California residents, depending on the Services used:

Identifiers, like your Reddit username, email address, IP address, and cookie information.
Commercial information, including information about transactions you undertake with us.
Internet or other electronic network activity information, such as information about your activity on our Services and limited information about your activity on the services of advertisers who use our advertising technology.
Geolocation information based on your IP address, or more specific location information if you authorize your device to provide it to us.
Audiovisual information in pictures, audio, or video content submitted to Reddit.
Professional or employment-related information or demographic information, but only if you explicitly provide it to us, such as by applying for a job or filling out a survey.
Inferences we make based on other collected data, for purposes such as recommending content, advertising, and analytics.
You can find more information about (a) what we collect and sources of that information, (b) the business and commercial purposes for collecting that information, and (c) the categories of third parties with whom we share that information in the "What We Collect (and How it is Used and Shared)" section above.

If you are a California resident, you have additional rights under the CCPA, including the right to request access to or deletion of your personal information, and information about our data practices, as well as the right not to be discriminated against for exercising your privacy rights. These rights can be exercised as described in the Data Subject and Consumer Information Requests section above.

Children
Children under the age of 13 are not allowed to create an account or otherwise use the Services. Additionally, if you are in the EEA, you must be over the age required by the laws of your country to create an account or otherwise use the Services, or we need to have obtained verifiable consent from your parent or legal guardian.

Changes to This Policy
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we do, we will let you know by revising the date at the top of the policy. If the changes, in our sole discretion, are material, we may also notify you by sending an email to the address associated with your account (if you have chosen to provide an email address) or by otherwise providing notice through our Services. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access or use our Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy. By continuing to use our Services after Privacy Policy changes go into effect, you agree to be bound by the revised policy.

Contact Us
To send a GDPR data subject request or CCPA consumer request, follow the steps in the "Your Rights - Data Subject and Consumer Information Requests" section above.

If you have other questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at legal@reddit.com or at:

Reddit, Inc.
548 Market St. #16093
San Francisco, California 94104

We have also appointed a representative in the EU to receive inquiries about our data practices:

Reddit Ireland Limited
Attn: Reddit EU Data Inquiries
70 Sir John Rogerson's Quay
Dublin 2
Ireland
eurepresentative@reddit.com

Reddit Content Policy
Reddit is a vast network of communities that are created, run, and populated by you, the Reddit users.

Through these communities, you can post, comment, vote, discuss, learn, debate, support, and connect with people who share your interests, and we encourage you to find-or even create-your home on Reddit.

While not every community may be for you (and you may find some unrelatable or even offensive), no community should be used as a weapon. Communities should create a sense of belonging for their members, not try to diminish it for others. Likewise, everyone on Reddit should have an expectation of privacy and safety, so please respect the privacy and safety of others.

Every community on Reddit is defined by its users. Some of these users help manage the community as moderators. The culture of each community is shaped explicitly, by the community rules enforced by moderators, and implicitly, by the upvotes, downvotes, and discussions of its community members. Please abide by the rules of communities in which you participate and do not interfere with those in which you are not a member.

Below the rules governing each community are the platform-wide rules that apply to everyone on Reddit. These rules are enforced by us, the admins.

Reddit and its communities are only what we make of them together, and can only exist if we operate by a shared set of rules. We ask that you abide by not just the letter of these rules, but the spirit as well.

Rules
Rule 1
Remember the human. Reddit is a place for creating community and belonging, not for attacking marginalized or vulnerable groups of people. Everyone has a right to use Reddit free of harassment, bullying, and threats of violence. Communities and users that incite violence or that promote hate based on identity or vulnerability will be banned.

Rule 2
Abide by community rules. Post authentic content into communities where you have a personal interest, and do not cheat or engage in content manipulation (including spamming, vote manipulation, ban evasion, or subscriber fraud) or otherwise interfere with or disrupt Reddit communities.

Rule 3
Respect the privacy of others. Instigating harassment, for example by revealing someone's personal or confidential information, is not allowed. Never post or threaten to post intimate or sexually-explicit media of someone without their consent.

Rule 4
Do not post or encourage the posting of sexual or suggestive content involving minors.

Rule 5
You don't have to use your real name to use Reddit, but don't impersonate an individual or an entity in a misleading or deceptive manner.

Rule 6
Ensure people have predictable experiences on Reddit by properly labeling content and communities, particularly content that is graphic, sexually-explicit, or offensive.

Rule 7
Keep it legal, and avoid posting illegal content or soliciting or facilitating illegal or prohibited transactions.

Rule 8
Don't break the site or do anything that interferes with normal use of Reddit.

Enforcement
We have a variety of ways of enforcing our rules, including, but not limited to

Asking you nicely to knock it off
Asking you less nicely
Temporary or permanent suspension of accounts
Removal of privileges from, or adding restrictions to, accounts
Adding restrictions to Reddit communities, such as adding NSFW tags or Quarantining
Removal of content
Banning of Reddit communities

Reddit Content Policy for Live Video
For content broadcast live on Reddit, all aspects of the Reddit Content Policy apply as usual.

Additionally:

No NSFW Content
Broadcasts on Reddit may not include NSFW ("Not Safe for Work") content. As noted in the Content Policy, this means content that contains nudity, pornography or sexually suggestive content, or graphic violence, which a reasonable viewer may not want to be seen accessing in a public or formal setting such as a workplace.

No Illegal or Dangerous Behavior
Broadcasts may not contain activities that are illegal, or that pose unreasonable risk of bodily harm to the stream subject or bystanders. Please note that this includes (but is not limited to) broadcasting while operating a vehicle and the illegal use of substances.

No Quarantine-Eligible Content
Broadcasts on Reddit may not include content that would otherwise trigger a Quarantine. As noted in the Content Policy, this means content that average redditors may find highly offensive or upsetting, or which promotes hoaxes.

Contextual Exceptions
When showing the world live as it happens, broadcasts may capture things that technically break these policies, but are nonetheless important. They may be newsworthy, educational, or otherwise socially valuable. Accordingly, we always take into account the context of a specific broadcast when making policy judgements.

Moderator Guidelines for Healthy Communities
Effective April 17, 2017.
Engage in Good Faith
Healthy communities are those where participants engage in good faith, and with an assumption of good faith for their co-collaborators. It's not appropriate to attack your own users. Communities are active, in relation to their size and purpose, and where they are not, they are open to ideas and leadership that may make them more active.

Management of your own Community
Moderators are important to the Reddit ecosystem. In order to have some consistency:

Community Descriptions:
Please describe what your community is, so that all users can find what they are looking for on the site.

Clear, Concise, and Consistent Guidelines:
Healthy communities have agreed upon clear, concise, and consistent guidelines for participation. These guidelines are flexible enough to allow for some deviation and are updated when needed. Secret Guidelines aren't fair to your users-transparency is important to the platform.

Stable and Active Teams of Moderators:
Healthy communities have moderators who are around to answer questions of their community and engage with the admins.

Association to a Brand:
We love that so many of you want to talk about brands and provide a forum for discussion. Remember to always flag your community as "unofficial" and be clear in your community description that you don't actually represent that brand.

Use of Email:
Please provide an email address for us to contact you. While not always needed, certain security tools may require use of email address so that we can contact you and verify who you are as a moderator of your community.

Appeals:
Healthy communities allow for appropriate discussion (and appeal) of moderator actions. Appeals to your actions should be taken seriously. Moderator responses to appeals by their users should be consistent, germane to the issue raised and work through education, not punishment.

Remember the Content Policy
You are obligated to comply with our Content Policy.

Management of Multiple Communities
We know management of multiple communities can be difficult, but we expect you to manage communities as isolated communities and not use a breach of one set of community rules to ban a user from another community. In addition, camping or sitting on communities for long periods of time for the sake of holding onto them is prohibited.

Respect the Platform
Reddit may, at its discretion, intervene to take control of a community when it believes it in the best interest of the community or the website. This should happen rarely (e.g., a top moderator abandons a thriving community), but when it does, our goal is to keep the platform alive and vibrant, as well as to ensure your community can reach people interested in that community. Finally, when the admins contact you, we ask that you respond within a reasonable amount of time.

Where moderators consistently are in violation of these guidelines, Reddit may step in with actions to heal the issues - sometimes pure education of the moderator will do, but these actions could potentially include dropping you down the moderator list, removing moderator status, prevention of future moderation rights, as well as account deletion. We hope permanent actions will never become necessary.

Cookie Notice
Last updated September 15, 2020.

This Cookie Notice explains how we use cookies and similar technologies as well as the options you have to control them.

What are cookies and how does Reddit use them?
A cookie is a small text file that a site stores on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. Browsers support cookies and similar technologies (such as local storage and pixels) so that a site like Reddit can remember information about your visit and can use the information to improve your experience and to create aggregated anonymized statistics about usage of the site. In this Notice, we use the term "cookie" to refer both to cookies and similar technologies.

Cookies may be set by the site you are visiting (called "first-party cookies") or by a third party, such as those who provide analytics or advertising services or interactive content on the site ("third-party cookies"). In addition to using cookies on our sites, we may also serve our cookies (specifically, our advertising pixel) on third-party sites operated by Reddit advertisers who use our advertising technology.

Our first-party cookies include cookies that are strictly necessary, functional cookies, cookies related to analytics/performance and advertising-related cookies.

Strictly Necessary: These cookies are necessary for our services to function properly and securely and cannot be switched off in our systems. You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but then some parts of the site will not work. These include:


Cookie		
Purpose		
Expires	

token,
d2_token		
Stores a login token needed to act as a logged in user.		
2 years	

session,
reddit_session		
Stores information that identifies your session.		
When browsing session ends	


Functional: These cookies enable Reddit to provide enhanced functionality and personalization. If you do not allow these cookies then some or all of these features may not function properly.

Analytics and Performance: These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site.

Advertising: We use these cookies to deliver advertisements, to make them more relevant and meaningful to users, and to track the efficiency of our advertising campaigns, both on our services and on other sites or mobile apps. Our third-party advertising partners may use these cookies to build a profile of your interests and deliver relevant advertising on other sites.

Third-Party Cookies: Reddit's services also include cookies from third parties that we partner with directly or indirectly. Many of these third parties are companies that work with us or with advertisers who advertise on Reddit in order to help target ads or measure the results of an advertising campaign.

Third-Party Sites: Third parties who advertise on Reddit may use our advertising technology, including our advertising pixel, on their sites. We may serve advertising cookies when you visit their sites so that we can measure the effectiveness of ads on Reddit and to show you more relevant advertising on Reddit. The placement of these cookies is controlled by the third-party sites.

How do I control cookies and how my data is used?
There are a number of ways you can control how information is collected from cookies on Reddit and how that information is used.

Your browser settings
Your browser includes controls that allow you to manage the use of cookies by the sites that you visit. Most browsers have features that enable you to see and delete cookies stored on your device and to block cookies from all or selected sites. For more information, here are links to external help materials from some of the popular browsers:

Mozilla Firefox
Apple Safari
Google Chrome
Microsoft Edge
Your mobile device settings
Your mobile device may also include browser settings that allow you to manage the use of cookies, especially if the device supports installing apps such as iOS and Android devices. iOS and Android devices also include additional device settings that control whether advertising partners can use information about your app activity for advertising purposes. On iOS, you can search for a setting called Limit Ad Tracking. On Android, you can search for a setting called Opt out of Ads Personalization.

Third-party opt-outs
The major online advertising industry groups offer tools to limit how cookies are used for advertising purposes by participating third parties. More information is available on these sites from the Network Advertising Initiative, the Digital Advertising Alliance, and for users in the EU, the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance. Also, Google provides web users with the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on to prevent the collection of data via Google Analytics.

Reddit user settings
On Reddit, you can control your privacy settings and how Reddit uses data by visiting https://www.reddit.com/settings/privacy.

Reddit Premium and Virtual Goods Agreement
Effective October 15, 2020. Last Revised September 15, 2020
1. Reddit Premium
Reddit Premium is a subscription membership. When you purchase Reddit Premium, you expressly agree that you are authorizing recurring payments, and that payments will be made to Reddit by the payment method and at the recurring intervals you have agreed to, until the subscription is canceled by you or by Reddit.

You can manage your Reddit Premium subscription and Payment Information by accessing your Account's user settings or via your mobile app. We automatically process your Payment Information on the calendar day corresponding to the start of your subscription. If your subscription starts on a day not contained in the next month, you will be billed on the last day of that month. Mobile renewal processing dates may vary by up to 3 days. If your Payment Information is declined, you must provide new Payment Information or your Reddit Premium subscription will be canceled. If you provide new Payment Information and are successfully charged, your new subscription period will be based on the original renewal date and not the date of the successful charge.

You can cancel Reddit Premium any time. Your subscription automatically renews unless you cancel at least 24 hours before your subscription period ends. To cancel your subscription, follow the instructions in your Account's user settings. If you purchased Reddit Premium using your Apple ID, you can cancel your subscription through your device's Account Settings or in the Manage Subscriptions section of the Apple App Store. If you purchased Reddit Premium using Google Play, you can cancel your subscription by visiting the Subscriptions section of Google Play. Your subscription will remain active from the time you cancel until the start of the next billing period, and you will not receive a refund or credit for any remaining days in your current billing period.

2. Virtual Goods
Virtual Goods are virtual currency or items, including Reddit Coins and Awards. Virtual Goods have no monetary value (i.e., are not a cash account or equivalent) and do not constitute currency or property of any type). Users have no property, proprietary, intellectual property, ownership, or monetary interest in promotional or purchased Virtual Goods, which remain Reddit digital content subject to these Terms. Virtual Goods are non-refundable and non-transferable between Accounts. Virtual Goods awarded to other users will not be returned (e.g., if you award another user, you cannot take the Virtual Goods back). You may not sell, barter, or trade any Virtual Goods, or offer to sell or trade any Virtual Goods. Any such attempted transfer will be null and void.

Reddit may modify its Virtual Goods at its sole discretion, and such modifications may make some or all Virtual Goods more or less common, desirable, effective, or functional. The number of Virtual Goods required to use other Virtual Goods (e.g., Coins needed to award another user) may be increased or decreased, any Virtual Good may be withdrawn, and restrictions on any Virtual Good redemption may be imposed at any time, even though such changes may affect the value or utility of the Virtual Good, or the ability to obtain certain Virtual Goods.

Reddit does not guarantee that the Virtual Goods will continually be offered for any particular length of time. Reddit may modify, suspend, or terminate Virtual Goods for any or no reason, in its sole discretion, and without advance notice or liability. In accumulating Virtual Goods, users may not rely upon the continued availability of any Virtual Goods.

3. No Refunds
As stated in Reddit's User Agreement and Content Policy, you must follow and comply with the rules of the platform and the rules of the individual subreddits you participate in. Failure to do so may result in a temporary or permanent ban from Reddit or certain subreddits or the removal of certain Virtual Goods. In such instances, you might lose the benefits of Reddit Premium or Virtual Goods. There are no refunds.


Previews Terms of Use
Reddit's Previews Terms of Use ("Terms") apply to your access to and use of certain new features ("Preview Features") on Reddit. By using Preview Features, you understand that these features may be canceled at any time for any or no reason, in our sole discretion, without advance notice or liability to Reddit. Remember, these Terms are in addition to the Reddit User Agreement, which you have already agreed to.

1. Community Points
Community Points are a virtual item controlled by you and maintained on the Ethereum blockchain. Community Points totals and transactions are stored as standard ERC-20 tokens publicly and permanently on the Ethereum blockchain. Community Points are distributed on a monthly basis and are linked publicly to your username. The community can modify the distribution of Community Points from the default distribution before the Community Points are written into the Ethereum blockchain. You have six months after distribution to claim your Community Points before the claim expires.

Community Points have no monetary value (i.e., are not a cash account or equivalent), cannot be sold to other users, and cannot be exchanged for cash or for any other goods and services outside of Reddit's virtual goods or services. Reddit does not guarantee that Community Points, or any virtual goods or services that Community Points provide access to or use of (e.g., Special Memberships, animated emojis, and GIFs), will continually be offered or will be available for any particular length of time. Reddit may modify Community Points, and how many you receive, at its sole discretion, and such modifications may remove or add functionality. In accumulating Community Points, you may not and should not rely upon their continued availability.

1.1 Eligibility
You cannot use Community Points if you are not able to form legally binding contracts (for example, if you are under 18 years old); are temporarily or indefinitely suspended from using Reddit's websites, mobile apps, widgets, and other online products and services; or are a person with whom transactions are prohibited under economic or trade sanctions.

1.2 Vault Account
Your Vault account is only intended for Community Points. If you create a Vault account through the Reddit app, we generate a public address and a private key. The public address is your address on the Ethereum blockchain where your Community Points are stored. The private key is the only way to access and use your Community Points. Reddit does not automatically receive or store your private key. The private key is stored on your phone, and you are solely responsible for its safekeeping. If you have not safely stored a backup and you lose your phone, you accept and acknowledge that any Community Points associated with your Vault account will become permanently inaccessible.

We strongly advise you take one of the following precautions to prevent losing access to your Community Points: (a) store a secure, encrypted backup of your private key on Reddit, or (b) manually protect your Vault by generating a recovery phrase and store that recovery phrase in a safe place, such as a password manager. You are solely responsible for remembering your Vault account password or recovery phrase. Reddit cannot assist you with Vault account password or recovery phrase retrieval, reset, or recovery. You accept and acknowledge that any Community Points associated with your Vault account will become permanently inaccessible if you lose your phone and you do not have your Vault account password or recovery phrase.

Each user account can only have one Vault account. If you create a second Vault account it will overwrite the current Vault account associated with that user account. In that instance, the original Vault account is unrecoverable by Reddit. All Community Points in the overwritten Vault will no longer be associated with the user account.

1.3 Transactions
You control your Community Points and you can transfer them to other Vault accounts or any Ethereum blockchain address. We have no control over the Ethereum blockchain and cannot ensure any transaction details you submit via your Vault account will be completed. Once transaction details have been submitted to the Ethereum blockchain via your Vault account, we cannot assist you to cancel, reverse, or otherwise modify your transaction details. We strongly encourage you to review your transaction details carefully before submitting them.

1.4 Fees
We do not currently charge fees for creating a Vault account or for Vault transactions, but we reserve the right to do so in the future. You do not need to create a Vault account to use Community Points, however other Ethereum wallets may charge for Ethereum network costs associated with Community Points transactions.

1.5 Special Memberships
When you purchase a Special Membership, your subscription is subject to the Reddit Premium and Virtual Goods Agreement. If you redeem Community Points for a Special Membership subscription, you can manage your subscription in the subreddit's Membership tab.

Purchasing a Special Membership or redeeming Community Points for a subreddit's Special Membership does not provide you with the right to post or comment in that subreddit. Participating subreddits are run by moderators and your ability to post or comment, or the removal of a post or comment, is at the discretion of that subreddit's moderator(s).

As noted at the top of these Terms, it's important to remember that Special Memberships are a new feature that may not be supported in the future. There will be no refunds if Special Memberships are no longer usable on Reddit.

2. Powerups
Powerups are a subscription membership. When you purchase Powerups, your subscription is subject to the Reddit Premium and Virtual Goods Agreement.

Purchasing Powerups does not provide you with the right to post or comment in that subreddit. Participating subreddits are run by moderators and your ability to post or comment, or the removal of a post or comment, is at the discretion of that subreddit's moderator(s). Moderators also have the ability to opt out of certain perks, including GIFs in comments and Emojis. When you purchase Powerups, it is possible the subreddit will not reach the Powerup total necessary to unlock additional perks.

3. Predictions
You must be 18 years old to use Predictions. Predictions do not offer an opportunity to win real money or prizes. When you use Predictions, your username and prediction are viewable by other redditors. Remember, Reddit Coins used in conjunction with Predictions are Reddit's digital content subject to the Reddit Premium and Virtual Goods Agreement. Predictions are a new feature that may not be supported in the future. There will be no refunds if Coins are no longer usable for Predictions.

4. Modification or Discontinuation
We reserve the right to modify, suspend, or discontinue Preview Features (in whole or in part) at any time, with or without notice to you. Any future release, update, or other addition to functionality of Preview Features will be subject to these Terms, which may be updated from time to time. You agree that we will not be liable to you or to any third party for any modification, suspension, or discontinuation of Preview Features or any part thereof. There will be no refunds if Preview Features are no longer usable on Reddit.

5. User Suspension or Termination
As stated in Reddit's User Agreement and its Content Policy, you must follow and comply with the rules of the platform and the rules of the individual subreddits you participate in. Failure to do so may result in a temporary or permanent ban from Reddit or certain subreddits or the removal of your posts and comments, including those subreddits where you might have access to Preview Features. In such instances, you might lose the benefits of Preview Features. There are no refunds.

Guidelines for Law Enforcement
Last Revised April 2, 2020
These guidelines provide U.S. law enforcement with general information about Reddit, Inc. ("Reddit"), its business and user records, as well as the legal process required for U.S. law enforcement to compel Reddit to produce user information.

This guide is for informational purposes only. It creates no contractual obligation, nor is it a commitment by Reddit to take specific action in a given circumstance. This guide provides neither legal advice nor a comprehensive overview of all legal requirements. For some requests, there may be additional requirements beyond those set forth here. This guide does not address requests from non-governmental entities.

Reddit takes the privacy of its users seriously. Therefore, Reddit reviews all requests and legal process for facial validity and legal sufficiency and will object when appropriate. Notwithstanding these guidelines, Reddit does not waive and expressly reserves all available rights and objections.

What is Reddit?
Reddit operates several products and services, including Reddit.com, Redditgifts.com and associated mobile applications.

The most popular product is Reddit.com, an online forum where people can create communities (known as "subreddits") to communicate online. Each subreddit has its own page, subject matter, users, and moderators. Users can share content by publishing stories, links and/or media (called "posts") to a subreddit, and other users can comment on the posts. Users can also "upvote" or "downvote" comments and/or posts. The number of upvotes and downvotes a post receives helps determine its position within the subreddit.

Additional information about Reddit and its services can be found here, while information about Reddit.com can be found here.

What user information does Reddit collect?
The information Reddit collects varies depending on the services utilized. For example:

Reddit.com users are not required to provide their name or contact information (including email address), though users can choose to do so. Reddit does not automatically verify the information provided by its users, though users may choose to verify their email address.
Redditgifts.com users may be asked to provide personal information such as their name, address, telephone number, age, personal interests and email address. Users may also be required to provide log-in information for an existing Reddit.com account or create one before using this service. That some users may submit this information, however, does not mean Reddit necessarily has this information for all users.
When Reddit has information about a user, it can generally be separated into four categories:

Basic subscriber information - This includes the username/subscriber identity, IP logs (including creation IP), the user's name (if any), email address (if any), and billing information (if any).
Expanded subscriber information - Non-content related records and/or information about a user or their conduct. This includes (but isn't limited to) user preferences and communication headers.
Content of communications (public) - This includes (but isn't limited to) posts, comments, votes, and other information regarding the substance of a user's publicly available communications. This content is available without Reddit's assistance.
Content of communications (non-public) - This includes non-public messages/communications between users, as well as posts, comments, votes and other information regarding the substance of a user's communications on non-public subreddits.
Reddit generally collects minimal information from users and may have little or no non-public information available for many users. For more information about the information Reddit collects, please visit the privacy policy for Reddit.com and the privacy notice for Redditgifts.com.

Data Retention Information
User information is retained in accordance with Reddit's privacy policy. Some information is collected automatically, while other information is collected at the user's discretion.

How long does Reddit store IP addresses?
Except for the IP address used to create an account, Reddit will delete any IP addresses collected after 100 days.

What happens to a user's posts/comments once their account has been deactivated?
Once a user has deactivated their account, their username will be publicly disassociated with any posts or comments that were made while the account was active. However, the posts and comments will still be visible, unless such content was removed before deactivation.

What happens to other user information once their account has been deactivated?
Certain information about a user profile may be retained by Reddit as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. For more information, please visit our privacy policy. If you still have specific questions, please contact us at lawenforcement@reddit.com.

Preservation Requests
Consistent with 18 U.S.C. § 2703(f), Reddit will preserve records for up to 90 days pending issuance of legal process if Reddit receives a written preservation request from a U.S. law enforcement entity that meets the following requirements:

Signed by a U.S. law enforcement officer/agent;
Includes the Reddit username(s) and/or the URL(s) of any relevant post(s)/comment(s);
Identifies the records to be preserved;
Identifies the time period for which records are to be preserved (maximum 90 days);
Confirms that valid legal process is forthcoming;
Has a valid return official email address for the relevant U.S. law enforcement entity;
Sent on law enforcement letterhead to lawenforcement@reddit.com with the subject line: "Preservation Request - u/[username]"; and
(For extensions only) Clearly identifies the request as a preservation extension.
Unless Reddit receives an appropriate extension, the preservation will be released 90 days after the date of the request, and the preserved records will be subject to Reddit's normal retention or destruction schedules. Reddit strongly recommends that preservation extensions be submitted at least seven days before the expiration date.

Will users be notified of a preservation request on their account?
Not in the ordinary course. However, users may be notified of any subsequent legal process that is not accompanied by a valid non-disclosure order.

Requests for User Information
Requests for user information must be directed to Reddit, Inc. in San Francisco, California (see Contact Information section for service instructions). Reddit reviews all legal process to ensure facial validity and legal sufficiency under applicable laws and regulations. This includes (but isn't limited to) the federal Stored Communications Act, 18 U.S.C. §2701, et seq. ("SCA") and the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act, Cal. Penal Code § 1546, et seq. ("CalECPA").

Reddit also reviews all legal process and requests to ensure they are not objectionable for other reasons, such as requests that seek confidential or proprietary information, privileged information, or information protected from disclosure under the First Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.

All requests for user information must be narrowly tailored and specifically identify the account(s) at issue (u/[username]) and the information sought (i.e. basic subscriber information).

Reddit cannot respond to invalid, overbroad, or vague requests.

Legal Sufficiency
Federal Law Enforcement

The SCA establishes the following standard for legal process:

Subpoena (criminal, administrative, etc.)
Basic subscriber information
Court Order under 18 U.S.C. §2703(D)
Basic subscriber information
Expanded subscriber information
Search Warrant
Basic subscriber information
Expanded subscriber information
Contents of communications (public)
Contents of communications (non-public)
State Law Enforcement

Legal process from state law enforcement must comply with federal law as well as relevant state laws governing access to user records. For example, in California CalECPA establishes the following standard for legal process:

State Level Subpoena
Basic subscriber information (excluding all IPs addresses)
State Level Search Warrant
Basic subscriber information
Expanded subscriber information
Contents of communications (public)
Contents of communications (non-public)
Will users be notified of a request for information on their account?
Reddit's policy is to provide its users with notice of requests and legal process seeking their information unless prohibited from doing so by statute or court order. Reddit will generally give the user a reasonable period of time to file an objection before producing responsive records. Where a statute or court order prohibits notice for a limited time period, Reddit provides notice upon expiration of that period.

In certain emergency, exigent, or counterproductive circumstances, Reddit may exercise its discretion not to provide users with notice of a request for their information prior to production. However, Reddit reserves the right to provide notice to affected users after records are produced.

Production of Records
Reddit provides responsive records in electronic format. In accordance with 18 U.S.C. §2706, reimbursement for the costs associated with production may be requested.

Authentication of Records
The records that Reddit produces are self-authenticating and should not require the testimony of a records custodian. If you require a form certification, please include it with the legal process.

Witness Testimony
Reddit does not provide expert witness testimony and does not have witnesses on call who are available to testify.

Emergency Disclosure Requests
In accordance with 18 U.S.C. §2702(c)(4) and our Privacy Policy, Reddit may disclose limited user information if Reddit has a good faith belief that an emergency exists involving the imminent threat of death or serious physical injury to a person, and disclosure is required without delay. Reddit evaluates these requests on a case-by-case basis and may request additional information to verify the nature of the request and/or the identity of the person making the request. Reddit does not commit to producing records under any set of circumstances or within a particular timeline.

To request this information, please complete our Emergency Disclosure Form. Please DO NOT send an email to lawenforcement@reddit.com, as it may result in a delay in processing your request.

Please note: If the content identified in an Emergency Disclosure Request violates Reddit's Content Policy, it will be removed from the platform after a reasonable amount of time. Such action may result in the permanent removal of the content.


Contact Information
U.S. law enforcement must submit copies of requests and/or legal process directed to Reddit, Inc. via email to lawenforcement@reddit.com. This address is for official law enforcement officers/agents only. Reddit does not provide phone support.

Requests and legal process can also be served on Reddit via its agent, Corporation Service Company, 2710 Gateway Oaks Drive, Suite 150N, Sacramento, CA, 95833. Courtesy copies of requests or legal process can be mailed to 548 Market Street, #16093, San Francisco, CA 94104-5401.

Reddit provides these addresses as a convenience for delivery of courtesy copies. They are not intended to waive service requirements, and Reddit expressly reserves its right to insist on personal or proper service of legal process.

International Law Enforcement Requests
Non-U.S. law enforcement agencies may also submit requests and/or legal process in english via lawenforcement@reddit.com. Reddit may not respond to requests in languages other than english. Because Reddit is a U.S. company and its user information is stored and maintained in the U.S., a request under the Mutual Legal Assistance Treaty or letters rogatory may be required to compel the disclosure of user information.

Changes
Reddit may change these Guidelines for Law Enforcement at any time, without prior notice.
